Anne Henrietta Martin Papers BANC MSS P-G 282
The Bancroft Library
- General Papers, 1867-1951; Carton 1-8; Carton 9, folders 1-42
  - Organizations, 1904-1949
    - Republican National Committee, circa 1916 (Carton 7, Folder 6)
    - Seattle Peace Society, 1929 (Carton 7, Folder 7)
    - Stanford University, 1914-1941 (Carton 7, Folder 8)
    - Satte Historical Society of Colorado, 1937 (Carton 7, Folder 9)
    - Strengthen America (Carton 7, Folder 10)
    - Suffragist, 1914-1918 (Carton 7, Folder 11)
    - Tax Reform Association (Carton 7, Folder 12)
    - Teach Ultain, Ireland (Carton 7, Folder 13)
    - Truckee River General Electric Co., 1915 (Carton 7, Folder 14)
    - United Farms of Santa Clara County (Carton 7, Folder 15)
    - United States Food Administration, 1918 (Carton 7, Folder 16)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1940 (Carton 7, Folder 17)
    - Victoria League (Carton 7, Folder 18)
    - Washington Woman Suffrage Council, 1914 (Carton 7, Folder 19)
    - Washoe County Henderson Club, 1918 (Carton 7, Folder 20)
    - Wisconsin Suffrage Association (Carton 7, Folder 21)
    - Woman's Civic League (Carton 7, Folder 22)
    - Woman's Independent Campaign Committee (Carton 7, Folder 23)
    - Woman's Journal (Carton 7, Folder 24)
    - Woman's National Republican Campaign Committee (Carton 7, Folder 25)
    - Woman's Peace Party, 1915 (Carton 7, Folder 26)
    - Woman's Peace Union, 1927-1940 (Carton 7, Folder 27)
    - Woman's Press (Carton 7, Folder 28)
    - Woman's Section of the Navy League, 1915 (Carton 7, Folder 29)
    - Woman's Suffrage League of Wadsworth, 1914 (Carton 7, Folder 30)
    - Woman's Suffrage Party (Carton 7, Folder 31)
    - Women's Citizen Club, 1915 (Carton 7, Folder 32)
    - Women's Equal Opportunity League (Carton 7, Folder 33)
    - Women's Freedom League, 1929-1930 (Carton 7, Folder 34)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1921-1945 (Carton 7, Folder 35-49)
    - Women's Political Union (Carton 7, Folder 50)
    - Women's Social and Political Union, circa 1914 (Carton 7, Folder 51)
    - World Alliance for International Friendship through the Churches, 1936 (Carton 7, Folder 52)
    - World Health Organization, 1949 (Carton 7, Folder 53)
    - World Peace Through a People's Parliament, 1944 (Carton 7, Folder 54)
    - World War Veteran's Inc. and Auxilary, 1920 (Carton 7, Folder 55)
  - Serials, 1885-1950
    - The Carmelite, 1928-1931 (Carton 7, Folder 60)
    - Carmel Pine Cone, 1930 (Carton 7, Folder 61)
    - The Christian, 'Extra' edition (Carton 7, Folder 62)
    - Congressional Record, 1916-1950 (Carton 7, Folder 63)
    - Foreign Affairs- A Journal of International Understanding, 1922-1926 (Carton 7, Folder 64)
    - The Friend- A Religious and Literary Journal, 1929 (Carton 7, Folder 65)
    - The Independent, 1920 (Carton 7, Folder 66)
    - Labor's News, 1930 (Carton 7, Folder 67)
    - The Labour Woman, 1921 (Carton 7, Folder 68)
    - The Louisville Herald Literary Magazine, 1909 (Carton 7, Folder 69)
    - The Nation, 1922-1943 (Carton 7, Folder 70)
    - Nevada State Annual Labor Review, 1912 (Carton 7, Folder 71)
    - The New Republic, 1918-1922 (Carton 7, Folder 72)
    - The Pall Mall Gazette, 1885 (Carton 7, Folder 73)
    - Pathfinder- A News Review of World Affairs, 1939 (Carton 7, Folder 74)
    - The Phoenix, 1918 (Carton 8, Folder 1)
    - The Public- A Journal of Democracy, 1919 (Carton 8, Folder 2)
    - Reconstruction- A Herald of the New Time, 1918 (Carton 8, Folder 3)
    - The Searchlight in Congress, 1914-1918 (Carton 8, Folder 4)
    - The Woman Citizen, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 5)
    - The Woman's Journal, 1911-1914 (Carton 8, Folder 6)
    - The Worker, 1917 (Carton 8, Folder 7)
  - Writings, 1893-1949
    - Draft fragments (Carton 8, Folder 11-12)
    - Aspects of British and American Feminism (Carton 8, Folder 13)
    - Autobiographical Sketch (Carton 8, Folder 14)
    - Autobiography (Carton 8, Folder 15)
    - About Mary Austin (Carton 8, Folder 16)
    - Article re: Mary Austin/ Letter to the Editor of the Nation, 1934 (Carton 8, Folder 17)
    - Battle of the 'Futurist' Woman (Carton 8, Folder 18)
    - Brief Explanation of Proposed Legislation Concerning the Use of Public Social Houses as Civic and Social Centers (Carton 8, Folder 19)
    - A Brief Proposed Amendment to the Constitution Equal Rights Brief Submitted by the National Woman's Party (Carton 8, Folder 20)
    - Josephine Butler Article for Encyclopaedia Brittanica, 1943 (Carton 8, Folder 21)
    - A Contemporary View of the London Times, 1901 (Carton 8, Folder 22)
    - Do 'Equality Laws' Equalize? (Carton 8, Folder 23)
    - Article IV Economic Barriers to Equality (Carton 8, Folder 24)
    - The Economic Consequences of Reformations, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 25)
    - Discussion on Educational Institutions, 1894 (Carton 8, Folder 26)
    - England's German Policy (Carton 8, Folder 27)
    - England versus American Women in Politics (Carton 8, Folder 28)
    - English Women Point the Way, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 29)
    - Espionage Act and Censorship; Let the People Know (Carton 8, Folder 30)
    - Equality Laws versus Women in Government (Carton 8, Folder 31)
    - Equal Suffrage News (Carton 8, Folder 32)
    - Essays on Woman Suffrage (Carton 8, Folder 33)
    - An Everlasting Benefit, 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 34)
    - Family Income and Infant Mortality, 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 35)
    - Forensics, 1893-1894 (Carton 8, Folder 36)
    - Governor Oddie Refuses Nevada Women Proclamation (Carton 8, Folder 37)
    - The Harriet Letters and the English Law of Libel (Carton 8, Folder 38)
    - Human Emancipation in Nevada (Carton 8, Folder 39)
    - If I Were a Senator, 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 40)
    - Report of the Kent and Summerfield Irrigation District Bills (Carton 8, Folder 41)
    - Jane Addam's Work for Peace, 1923 (Carton 8, Folder 42)
    - Labor is Watching It's Leaders (Carton 8, Folder 43)
    - Land Monopoly and Its Evils, 1919 (Carton 8, Folder 44)
    - Liquor License Ordinance, 1915 (Carton 8, Folder 45)
    - Lord Haldane Speaks (Carton 8, Folder 46)
    - Memoirs of Anne Martin, 1948 (Carton 8, Folder 47)
    - Necessity of Winning the Western Campaigns (Carton 8, Folder 48)
    - Nevada Beautiful Desert of Buried Hope, 1923 (Carton 8, Folder 49)
    - New Democracy for Old Autocracy (Carton 8, Folder 50)
    - The Next Step for Women, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 51)
    - Notes on Summer Field Irrigation District (Carton 8, Folder 52)
    - Draft Statement to the Court on the Occasion of Charges of Obstruction (Carton 8, Folder 53)
    - Our Solider Settlement Policy, 1919 (Carton 8, Folder 54)
    - The Pacifists Position in War Time, circa 1914 (Carton 8, Folder 55)
    - Parties, Principles and the Woman Voter (Carton 8, Folder 56)
    - The Passing of Mrs. Catt, 1947 (Carton 8, Folder 57)
    - Personalities and Power, 1923 (Carton 8, Folder 58)
    - Plan of Articles on Women Today and Women Tomorrow (Carton 8, Folder 59)
    - Political Methods of American and British Feminists, 1924 (Carton 8, Folder 60)
    - Position of Englishwomen in Public Life (Carton 8, Folder 61)
    - Rapport de la Commission sur le travail Futur (Carton 8, Folder 62)
    - Reno, Nevada by a Resident (Carton 8, Folder 63)
    - Report and Review concerning State Mental Hospital, 1948 (Carton 8, Folder 64)
    - Report of Anne Martin Western Regional Director, WILPF (Carton 8, Folder 65)
    - Report to Mary Beard re: Encyclopaedia Britannica treatment of women (Carton 8, Folder 66)
    - The Situation in Vienna, 1929 (Carton 8, Folder 67)
    - State Mental Hospital article, 1946 (Carton 8, Folder 68)
    - Statements by Anne Martin, 1922-1950 (Carton 8, Folder 69-72)
    - The Status of Women (Carton 8, Folder 73)
    - The Story of Jim and Phil (Carton 8, Folder 74)
    - The Story of Nevada Equal Suffrage Campaign (Carton 8, Folder 75)
    - Suffrage and Government (Carton 8, Folder 76)
    - The Suffragette Problem in England, 1909 (Carton 8, Folder 77)
    - Suffragists Agree, Protect the Schools, 1914 (Carton 8, Folder 78)
    - Synopsis of Article: Evolution and the Women's Movement (Carton 8, Folder 79)
    - Synopsis of Article: Women's Mind versus Men's (Carton 8, Folder 80)
    - Understanding Herbert Hoover, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 81)
    - A Vital Women's Issue, 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 82)
    - We Couldn't Afford a Doctor, 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 83)
    - What I Would Do if I Were a United States Senator, 1918 (Carton 8, Folder 84)
    - What Use Will Women Make of Political Power in 1920 (Carton 8, Folder 85)
    - What Women Should Vote For, 1919 (Carton 8, Folder 86)
    - International Agreement for the Suppression of White Slave Traffic (Carton 8, Folder 87)
    - White Slave Traffic, 1943-1944 (Carton 8, Folder 88)
    - Women's Vote and Woman's Chains, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 89)
    - Why Women are Needed in Government, 1913 (Carton 8, Folder 90)
    - Wisconsin Laws Relating to Civic and Social Development (Carton 8, Folder 91)
    - Woman's Inferiority Complex, 1921 (Carton 8, Folder 92)
    - The Woman's Peace Congress at Dublin, 1926 (Carton 8, Folder 93)
    - The Woman's Suffrage Movement in Nevada (Carton 8, Folder 94)
    - Women's Wage Controversy in California, 1923 (Carton 8, Folder 95)
    - Women and Their Magazines (Carton 8, Folder 96)
    - Women in Two Elections, 1923 (Carton 8, Folder 97)
    - Women Give Your Differences (Carton 8, Folder 98)
    - Women's Suffrage Movement in England, 1909 (Carton 8, Folder 99)
    - The World Over: The Election in the United States, 1922 (Carton 8, Folder 100)
    - The World Over: Male Feminism in an American Magazine (Carton 8, Folder 101)
    - The Young Man of the Day and the Suffragette (Carton 8, Folder 102)
    - Poetry, 1935-1942 (Carton 8, Folder 103-111)
    - Poetry, 1903-1943 (Carton 9, Folder 1-38)
    - Speeches, 1913-1949 (Carton 9, Folder 39-42)
- Personalia, 1834-1951; Carton 9, folders 43-56; Carton 10; Volumes 1-12
  - Bank Books, circa 1918 (Carton 9, Folder 43)
  - Diaries, 1888-1951 (Carton 9, Folder 44-53)
  - Diplomas, 1896-1945 (Carton 9, Folder 54)
  - Expense Book, 1834 (Carton 9, Folder 55)
  - Notebook (Carton 9, Folder 56)
  - Order Book (Carton 10, Folder 1)
  - Passports, 1926-1929 (Carton 10, Folder 2)
  - Ribbon as Conference Participant, 1910 (Carton 10, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook, 1900 (Carton 10, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, 1913-1940 (Carton 10, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers, circa 1941 (Carton 10, Folder 6)
  - Address and Membership cards, Housed within carton in two cardfile boxes (Carton 10)
  - Scrapbook- Senatorial Race, 1918 (Carton 10)
  - Scrapbooks- Suffrage Clippings, 1910, 1913 (Carton 10)
  - Scrapbook- Suffrage Clippings, 1914 (Volume 1-2)
  - Scrapbook- Suffrage Clippings, 1916 (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook- Nevada Equal Suffrage Society Clippings, 1914 (Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook- General Politics, 1920 (Volume 10)
  - Scrapbook- Senatorial Election Race, 1918-1920 (Volume 5-9)
  - Scrapbook- Woman's Journal, 1912-1913 (Volume 11)
  - Scrapbook- Congressional Record, 1919 (Volume 12)